자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
A trucker driving by
saw the body, called it in.
지나가던 트럭 운전사가
시체를 발견하고 신고했어
Easy to miss.
그냥 지나치기 쉬운 곳이네요
The coroner's tied up
on a multiple in Pahrump,
검시관은 파럼프에서 생긴
연쇄 추돌 사고로 발이 묶여 있긴 한데
but they're en route.
Officer Jensen was first responding.
오는 중이래
젠슨 경찰관이 최초 신고를 받았어
When he saw the condition of the body,
시체의 상태를 보고서
he backed out of the scene,
stepping in his own footprints.
현장에서 빠져나왔는데
신발 자국이 남았어
Anyway, we've been beating the
bush looking for her personal effects,
어쨌든 개인 소지품을 찾으려고
덤불을 뒤지는 중이지만
but so far nothing.
아직까지는 나온 게 없어
Jane Doe it is.
신원 미상이군요
You must be Keppler.
당신이 케플러 씨인가 보군요
Willows? / Catherine.
윌로우즈 씨? / 캐서린이라고 불러요
Sorry I'm late.
Got stuck on the Strip.
늦어서 죄송합니다
시내 중심가에서 차가 막혀서요
Welcome to Las Vegas.
라스베가스에 온 걸 환영해요
Is that how they're doing
things in Baltimore these days?
요즘 볼티모어에선
그렇게 하나 보죠?
Out here,we don't touch the body
until the coroner releases it.
여기선 검시관이 검시를 마칠 때까지는
시체에 손을 대지 않아요
Sorry. Just...
죄송합니다, 그냥
trying to get a better look at her face.
얼굴을 더 자세히 보려고 한 겁니다
There's bruising around
the neck,relatively fresh.
목 주변에 비교적
선명한 멍이 있어요
No other obvious wounds on the body.
시체에 다른 뚜렷한 상처는 없어요
This girl's barely out of high school.
고등학교나 막 졸업한 애일 거예요
Catnip. / Excuse me?
캣닙 같네요 / 네?
The way they attract men
at that age; it's like catnip.
이 나이 때는 남자를 끌어들이는
매력이 꼭 캣닙 같단 얘기예요
That's a terrifying thought.
무서운 생각인데요
You have kids?
아이가 있으신가요?
A daughter,15.
딸이요. 15살이죠
You must be a hit on career day.
학부모 교사 날 인기인이시겠군요
I try not to bring my work home with me.
제 일을 집으로 가져가지는 않으려고 노력해요
Yeah.
그렇군요
How about you?
당신은요?
What? / Any kids?
뭐가요? / 아이가 있나요?
Patchy discolorations on the skin.
피부 여기저기 변색이 되어있는데요
Looks like dehydration.
탈수증 같아요
White fibers.
흰색 섬유네요
I'm guessing cotton.
면 같은데요
Looks like she's been swabbed down
with something that evaporated,
이 애를 휘발성 물질로 닦은 것 같아요
maybe alcohol.
알코올 같은 걸로요
Unlike most men, this one knows
how to clean up after himself.
대개의 범인들과는 다르게
뒤처리를 할 줄 아는 놈이군요
싱크편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
배영숙(neons71@lycos.co.kr)
월리암 피터슨(길 그리섬 役)
CSI 레벨3(반장), 전문분야: 곤충학
마그 헬겐버거(캐서린 윌로우스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 혈흔 분석
게리 도단(워릭 브라운 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 음향/시각 자료분석
조지 이즈(닉 스톡스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 머리카락, 섬유질 분석
조자 폭스(새라 사이들 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 물질성분 분석
에릭 스즈맨다(그렉 샌더스 役)
CSI 레벨1, 전문분야: DNA분석
로버트 데이비드 홀(알 로빈스 役)
검시관, 전문분야: 법의학
루이스 롬바드(소피아 커티스 役)
라스베가스시 경찰청 형사
폴 길포일(짐 브래스 役)
라스베가스시 경찰청 경감
CSI: Crime Scene Investigation
7x12 Sweet Jane
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2007/01/18
So how long is this fellow Keppler
supposed to be with us?
저 케플러라는 친구와
얼마 동안 같이 일하게 되는 거죠?
Well, he was hired to
staff the new day shift, but...
낮 근무조에 새로 배정된 사람이긴 한데
since we're one share with Grissom away,
그리섬 반장님이 나가신 동안 한 사람이 비니까
Ecklie wanted us to
break him in for a few weeks.
몇 주간 우리와 같이 일하면서 여기 일에
적응하게 해주길 애클리 부소장이 바라더라고
Got a broken fingernail.
손톱이 부러져 있어요
Please tell me she got
a piece of her attacker.
공격한 사람의 상피가
있다고 말해줘
If the nail had been torn off,
the break would be smooth.
손톱이 찢겨 나간 거라면
부러진 곳이 매끄러울 거야
It's jagged; she's a biter.
들쭉날쭉해. 자기가 물어뜯은 거야
So flash this photo around the Alphabets.
알파벳 주변에 이 사진들을 보여줘 봐
If she's a pro or a local,
somebody will recognize her.
매춘부거나 지역 주민이라면
누군가 알아볼 거야
Alphabets?
알파벳이요?
Yeah,it's a neighborhood.
You know, A Street, B Street, D Street.
네, 인근 지역을 말하는 거요
A 거리, B 거리, D 거리 같은 거지
A through F is pretty bad--
homeless,junkies, scumbags,
A부터 F까지는 꽤 나빠요
노숙자, 마약상용자, 인간쓰레기들
the hookers we chase off the Strip.
시내 중심가에서 쫓아낸 매춘부들이 있죠
I mean,if you're down and out in Vegas,
그러니까 라스베가스에서 망하고 나면
sooner or later,
you're gonna end up here.
조만간에 결국 여기서
끝이 난다는 말이오
Hear you got one of the fastest
growing murder rates in the country.
이 나라에서 범죄율이 가장 빨리
증가하는 곳 중 하나라는 말이네요
Yeah,we're very competitive.
맞아요, 우리가 경쟁력이 높은 편이죠
Is that a Philly accent I hear?
필라델피아 사투리로 들리는데?
Trenton,born and bred.
트렌튼에서 나고 자랐죠
My condolences. I'm from Newark.
안 됐구려. 난 뉴워크 출신이오
- How you doing?
- How are you?
- 안녕하세요
- 안녕하시오
Thought I heard something familiar.
귀에 익다 싶었어요
But you got to love Vegas,
isn't that right,Catherine?
하지만 라스베가스를 좋아하게 될 거요
그렇지 않나, 캐서린?
My hometown.
제 고향이죠
I mean, the pizza's terrible,
but everything else is paradise.
피자는 끔찍하지만
다른 것들은 낙원이죠
So I see you've got the soil
and vegetation exemplars.
토양과 식물 표본을 채집하는 걸 봤어요
- Thank you.
- Three distinct locations.
- 고마워요
- 위치가 다른 세 곳에서 채집했어요
Not that it's gonna make much difference.
크게 도움이 될 것 같지는 않지만요
I get the feeling our guy's not the type
to track away dirt on his shoes.
범인이 신발에 흙 자국을 남겨 놓을
타입은 아닐 것 같거든요
Probably not.
아마도 아니겠죠
Our best bet's the body.
제일 큰 단서가 될 만한 건 시체인데
Which we're probably not
gonna get much from, either.
거기서도 많은걸
찾아낼 수 없을 것 같아요
So is the pizza really that bad?
근데 피자가 정말 그렇게 별로예요?
I like it.
난 좋아해요
No obvious traces of semen?
정액 흔적이 뚜렷이 남아있진 않나요?
No.
없어요
No visible skin under the fingernails,
so she probably didn't fight back.
손톱 아래에 눈에 띄는 상피가 없는 걸로 봐서
저항하지 않은 것 같군요
There were no defensive
wounds on her forearms,
팔뚝에 방어흔이 없고
no ligature marks on her wrists or ankles.
손목과 발목에 묶은 흔적도 없어요
Maybe he didn't want to mark her up.
흠집을 내고 싶지 않았을 거예요
I mean,look at her.
그러니까, 보세요
So young.
젊고
Innocent.
청순하죠
He wanted to take his time.
천천히 즐기고 싶었을 겁니다
He drugged her.
약을 먹였어요
We should expand tox to include
volatiles and sedative hypnotics.
약물 검사에 휘발성 물질과
진정 수면제를 포함시켜야겠어요
- You got something?
- Highlights and lowlights.
- 뭔가 찾으셨나요?
- 머리에 브릿지 염색을 했어요
That's a hair process that isn't cheap.
싸게 할 수 있는 머리는 아니죠
Nominal hair growth
is roughly half-a-millimeter a day.
머리카락은 대개
하루에 0.5밀리미터가 자라요
And based on the length of her roots,
시작되는 부분에서의 길이로 볼 때
it's been about two months
since she's had it done.
머리를 한 지 두 달 정도 지났어요
Not the kind of girl who goes
missing without a report.
행방불명이 신고되지 않을
부류의 아가씨는 아니겠군요
Your vic's name is
Veronica Sorensen, age 17.
피해자 이름은
베로니카 소렌슨이고 17살이에요
Last reported in Victorville.
최근에 빅터빌에서 신고가 들어왔습니다
- About two months ago?
- Yeah, yeah.
- 두 달 전쯤에?
- 네, 맞아요
She's a... / Runaway?
피해자는 / 가출이야?
Yeah. Parents reported her missing.
네, 부모가 실종 신고를 했어요
P.D.'s already made the notifications.
경찰에서 부모에게 벌써 알렸어요
So,what's the verdict on this Keppler guy?
케플러라는 사람에 대한 평결은 어떻게 났나요?
What? You're usually pretty
quick to size people up.
뭐예요? 평소엔 사람 판단하시는데
꽤 빠르시잖아요
Jury's still out,
but he knows what he's doing.
배심원이 아직 의논 중이긴 한데
하는 일이 뭔지는 확실히 아는 사람이더군
In other news,
local Las Vegas police officers
다음 소식입니다
라스베가스 지역 경찰에서는
are still trying to identify the
body of a nude woman found
어제 아침 51번 고속도로에서
발견된 나체 여성 시신의
off Highway 51 early yesterday morning.
The police say they received a call at 3:32 a.m.
신원을 아직 찾는 중입니다
경찰은 오전 3시 32분, 51번 고속도로를 지나던
from a truck driver who happened to be
driving down Highway 51 when he spotted
트럭 운전사가 도로에서 떨어진 곳에서
젊은 여성의 시체를 발견하고
the young woman's body just off the road.
신고 전화를 했다고 밝혔습니다
I'm Detective Curtis.
I'm... so sorry for your loss.
커티스 형사입니다
따님 일은 정말 유감입니다
That girl on the TV,
that is not my Veronica.
텔레비전에 나온 저 아이는
제 딸 베로니카가 아니에요
They wouldn't call us if they weren't sure.
확실하지 않았다면 알리지 않았을 거요
We were able to match her fingerprints.
지문을 확인할 수 있었습니다
Then you've made a mistake.
그럼 실수하신 걸 거예요
The prints that we gave to the police,
they were from a school safe kit.
경찰에 드린 지문은
학교 미아 방지 명찰에 있던 겁니다
She was ten years old.
10살 때 거죠
They could've changed,right?
변했을 수도 있잖아요?
Fingerprints don't change.
지문은 변하지 않습니다
There was a tattoo on
her right ankle-- an iguana.
오른쪽 발목에 문신이
있었습니다. 이구아나요
Oh,no.
오, 안 돼요
- We just want to take her home.
- Of course.
- 딸아이를 집에 데려가고 싶습니다
- 물론이죠
As soon as we've completed the autopsy.
검시가 끝나면 바로 데려가실 수 있습니다
No. No,you're not gonna cut her open.
아뇨, 그 앨 검시할 순 없어요
- Sir, this is a homicide.
- We're not giving our permission.
- 이건 살인 사건입니다
- 저흰 허락하지 않겠어요
I'm afraid you don't have a choice.
죄송합니다만 선택의 여지가 없습니다
But I promise you, we'll treat
her with the utmost respect.
하지만 최대한 존중을 가지고
다룰 것을 약속 드리겠습니다
And what can I do for you?
뭘 도와줄까?
Let me know when you release the body.
언제 검시가 끝나는지 알려주세요
It's going to be a while.
I haven't even opened her up yet.
시간이 걸릴 거야
아직 열지도 않았거든
Well,just let me know.
그냥 알려만 주세요
And stop whistling.
휘파람은 그만 불어 주세요
C.O.D. was asphyxiation due to
strangulation, but it wasn't quick.
사망 원인은 교살에 의한 질식이지만
빠르지는 않았어
The overlapping patterns of fours
and ones suggest multiple events.
손가락이 겹친 모양을 보면
여러 번 조른 거야
I imaged subcutaneous
bruises under UV
자외선으로 영사해보니
식도 주변 몇 군데
from several positions
around the throat.
피하에 멍이 들어있더군
Killer choked and released
at least three times.
살인자가 적어도 세 번은
목을 졸랐다 놨다 했던 거지
That's consistent with
sexual asphyxiation.
성적 교살과 일치해
S.A.E. is about what you'd expect.
성폭행 검사는 생각하고 있는 대로야
Vaginal trauma, no semen,
but traces of spermicide.
질에 상처가 있고 정액은 없지만
살정자제 흔적이 남아있어
Guy used a condom.
콘돔을 사용했어
What about tox?
약물 검사는 어때요?
Well,blood was positive for MDMA.
혈액에서 MDMA 양성 반응이 나왔어
Ecstasy. That's it? / Yep.
엑스터시군요, 맞나요? / 맞아
I can't believe that she was compliant.
순순히 당했다니 믿을 수가 없어
- Thanks, Doc.
- You got it.
- 감사합니다, 박사님
- 천만에
You ever see a cat playing with a mouse?
쥐를 가지고 노는 고양이 보신 적 있어요?
Point isn't to kill the mouse,
just keep the game going.
쥐를 죽이는 것보다는
그냥 가지고 노는 데 목적이 있죠
I'm guessing you've got cats.
고양이를 기르나 봐요
No. I just like the metaphor.
아뇨. 은유를 좋아할 뿐이죠
Same game every time.
매번 같은 놀이를 하다가
Cat goes home,
leaves its kill on the doorstep.
문 앞에 사냥감을 놔두고
집으로 돌아가는 거죠
Our guy's done this before.
I'm with you there.
놈이 이런 짓을 한 전력이 있다는 거죠
저도 거기에 동의해요
What got our cat's attention this time?
이번에 고양이의 관심을 끈 건 무엇일까요?
Around puberty,
most guys fixate on a particular
사춘기 즈음에
대부분의 남자들은 자신을 흥분시키는
body type that turns them on.
특정한 신체 유형에 집착하죠
Tall, skinny, short, red hair.
Whatever floats your boat.
크다든가, 말랐거나, 작거나, 빨간 머리거나
어떤 것이든지요
It's imprinted.
Hard to let go of.
각인이 돼서 벗어나기 어렵죠
Okay.
좋아요
So we know what his type is
그러니까 우린 범인의 취향을 알고 있고
and we know what he
likes to do with them.
뭘 하는 걸 좋아하는지도
알고 있어요
Okay,we've got three that fit the type.
유형에 맞는 세 건을 찾았어요
The cases were years apart.
사건들은 몇 년씩 간격이 떨어져 있어요
1999, 1989...and 1975.
1999년, 1989년 그리고 1975년
Let's bring up their photographs.
사진을 불러 보도록 하죠
Look at the similarity
in the body positions.
자세의 유사성을 보세요
They look posed,
작별 인사를 하듯이
almost as if they were waving good-bye
손을 흔드는 자세처럼 보이는데요
Jane Doe '99 was discovered naked
99년의 신원 미상자는 콘티넨탈 호텔 뒤의
in a stretch of dirt off Paradise
behind the old Hotel Continental.
파라다이스 가에서 떨어진 흙 길에서
나체로 발견되었어요
Based on the photos,
her hair was matted with dirt,
사진을 보면 머리가
흙으로 헝클어져 있어요
which suggests that it was wet
when she was dumped.
버려졌을 때
젖어있었다는 거죠
It's likely that her body was washed.
몸을 씻긴 것 같아요
That's consistent with the latest victim.
그 점은 최근 희생자와 일치하네
Any traces of alcohol or cotton swabs?
알코올이나 면으로 닦아낸 흔적은요?
There's nothing indicated,
but there's almost nothing in this file.
나와 있는 건 없어요
이 파일 안에 있는 게 거의 없거든요
Based on T.O.D., the body was
found less than four hours after death.
사망 시간에 따르면 시체는
사망 후 네 시간이 못돼서 발견되었는데
Yet other than a general canvass,
일반적인 조사를 제외하고는
not a single person was interviewed.
한 사람도 심문하지 않았더라고요
The homicide detective's
summary is less than a page.
강력반 형사의 사건 요약이
한 페이지도 안 되던데요
- Sounds like shoddy police work.
- Sounds like no police work.
- 경찰이 일을 대충 한 거 같네요
- 아예 일을 하지 않은 것 같은데요
After the autopsy, C.O.D.
confirmed asphyxiation by strangulation.
검시 후에 사망 원인은
교살에 의한 질식사로 확인되었습니다
There was absolutely
no follow-up whatsoever.
분명히 후속 수사는 전혀 없었어요
Well, there was a follow-up
in spades on Jane Doe '89.
89년의 신원 미상자에게는
확실한 후속 수사가 있었어요
She was found in a vacant lot
off 28th Street near Bould Highway.
볼드 고속도로 근처 28번가 바깥의
공터에서 발견되었습니다
Uh,stripped of her clothing.
Like the others,
다른 피해자와 마찬가지로
옷은 벗겨져 있었고
several peri-mortem bruises,
but check out this hair.
사망 당시에 생긴 멍이 여러 개 있었습니다
근데 이 머리카락을 보세요
Yeah,it's crimped.
I remember those days.
그래, 곱슬머리를 했군
그 시절 기억이 나네
There's no way that
style survives a shower.
이런 머리 모양이 샤워 후에
남아있을 수는 없지
Killer didn't wash that one down.
살인자가 그 피해자는 씻기지 않았어요
Methods evolve.
Practice makes perfect.
수법은 발전해요
연습하다 보면 완벽해지는 거죠
Again, cops didn't come
up with a single suspect.
경찰에선 역시 한 명의 용의자도
찾아내지 못했습니다
There were detailed
sketches of the crime scene,
사건 현장이 자세히 묘사되어 있고
microscopy on errant hairs and fibers,
머리카락과 섬유의 현미경 검사
even ran the vic's prints through WIN.
희생자의 지문까지 WIN에서 찾아봤더군요
'89... that database was
barely on the Internet.
89년이라면 인터넷에
자료가 거의 없었을 텐데
The guy that worked on
this case was very thorough.
이 사건 담당자는 아주 철저했어
He just didn't close it.
사건을 쉽게 종결하지는 않았어
Okay,Jane Doe '75.
좋아, 75년 신원 미상자로 가보자고
Well...she was found in an alley
off of Bridger near Fremont Street.
프레몬트 가 근처 브리저의
골목에서 발견되었습니다
Based on the level of decomp,
시신의 부패 정도로 볼 때
she'd been lying there about
two days before they found her.
발견될 때까지 이틀 정도
거기 놓여 있었던 것 같네요
Only thing about this one is,
she had her clothes on.
이 피해자가 다른 피해자와 유일하게
다른 점은 옷을 입고 있었다는 겁니다
- Might have been his first.
- Or maybe the first one found
- 첫 번째 피해자일지도 모르겠어요
- 아님 처음 발견된 피해자일 수도 있죠
Isolated contusions on her neck,
arms and shoulders.
목, 팔과 어깨에
산발적인 타박상이 있었고
C.O.D. listed as heroin overdose.
사망 원인은 헤로인 과다 복용으로 되어있습니다
Junkies do bruise easily.
마약 상용자들은 쉽게 멍이 들죠
And the "waving good-bye"
hand position is a natural way to fall.
작별 인사를 하는 손은
넘어지면 자연스럽게 생긴 자세고요
It's possible that this
one is a coincidence. / It's not.
이 사건은 우연한 일치일 수도
있겠는데요 / 그렇지 않습니다
- How do you know?
- Because I do.
- 어떻게 알죠?
- 알고 있으니까요
This guy pays attention to the details.
Knows what he likes, he doesn't mix it up.
범인은 세부적인 것에 주의를 기울입니다
좋아하는 걸 구별하고 혼동하는 일은 없습니다
Thing that gets me
is the discipline, though.
제가 관심이 가는 건
자제성이긴 하지만요
He's got a habit,
but he seems to be able to control it.
범인에겐 범죄 기질이 있지만
그걸 통제할 수 있는 것 같습니다
Only needs to kill once
every ten years or so,
10년 정도마다 한 번씩만
살인을 할 필요가 있는 거죠
and when he does, he's got a type.
그럴 때면 공통된 유형이 있는 거고요
- Pretty but not pricey.
- And not likely to be missed.
- 아름답지만 비싸지는 않은 여자로요
- 그리고 놓칠 것 같지 않은 여자요
You're a CSI, not a profiler.
당신은 범죄심리분석가가 아니라 CSI예요
- What's the difference?
- Evidence.
- 뭐가 다르죠?
- 증거요
I want leads and IDs.
단서와 신원이 필요해요
Follow up on what you've got.
알아낸 것에 대해 조사해줘요
When I left this place,
it was all grey walls and cinder blocks.
제가 여길 떠났을 땐
온통 회색 벽과 콘크리트 블록들이었죠
Very fancy.
아주 멋지네요
What made you transfer to Henderson?
왜 헨더슨으로 옮기셨나요?
Cost of living, better commute.
생활비도 덜 들고 통근이 편해서요
I socked away a few bucks,
bought a nice place in Green Valley.
돈을 좀 모아서
그린 밸리에 멋진 곳을 샀습니다
Ah,I take it you're a shortcuts kind of guy.
아, 편한 걸 좋아하시는 분이군요
I guess you could say that.
I like to get to the heart of things right away.
그렇게 말할 수도 있겠죠
바로 핵심으로 들어가는 게 좋겠네요
Any reason that you didn't
get to the heart of this?
이 사건의 핵심으로는 들어가지
않았던 이유가 있었나요?
- October 17, 1999.
- You remember the date?
- 1999년 10월 17일 사건이군요
- 날짜를 기억하시나요?
Yeah. / Why is that?
네 / 그건 왜죠?
Hey, I'm not sure I like your tone.
이봐요, 당신 말투가 좀 이상한데요
Answer the question, Detective.
질문에 대답하시죠, 형사님
It's my son's birthday.
제 아들 생일이거든요
Day I caught the case,
my wife went into labor.
이 사건을 맡은 날
아내가 진통을 시작했어요
It was rough.
There were complications.
좋지 않았죠
합병증이 있었거든요
Anyway,I was out for
weeks taking care of her.
어쨌든, 아내를 돌보느라
몇 주 동안 쉬었습니다
Used up all my vacation time.
휴가 기간을 전부 썼죠
When I got back,there were a
half dozen cases on my desk.
돌아와 보니 책상 위에
사건 여섯 개가 놓여있더군요
My captain told me to let it go.
상관이 그 사건은 놔두라고 하더군요
Look.
이봐요
We canvassed the neighborhood.
No name.
주변을 조사해 봤지만
이름도 안 나왔어요
She was homeless,
hooking for drug money.
마약 할 돈을 구하려고
매춘을 하던 노숙자였다고요
You do not know that.
You didn't even ask for tox.
그건 모르죠
약물 검사도 신청하지 않았잖아요
We didn't need to do a test.
We found her at Paradise and Flamingo.
검사할 필요가 없었습니다
피해자는 파라다이스와 플라밍고 가에서 발견됐어요
What else would she be doing there?
거기서 뭘 하고 있었겠어요?
Okay, here we are.
좋아요, 여기 있네요
Autopsy samples for Doe, Jane.
신원 미상자의 검시 표본
99-103
99-103번
Uh,most recent vic had
traces of E in her system.
가장 최근의 희생자
체내에는 엑스터시 흔적이 있었어
If this one does, too,
there might be a connection.
이 피해자도 그런 거라면
연관성이 있을지도 몰라
To a drug dealer from ten years ago?
10년 전 마약 판매상과요?
That's kind of weak.
가능성이 약해 보이는데요
Weak is the best that we have right now.
그 약한 가능성이 지금 우리에겐 최선이야
Hodges ran the formalin-fixed tissue
sample from Jane Doe '99 through GCMS.
하지스가 99년 신원 미상자의 포르말린 처리된
조직 표본을 GCMS에 돌려봤는데요
There's no traces of Ecstasy,
but he did find chloral hydrate.
엑스터시의 흔적은 없었지만
클로랄 하이드레트를 찾았어요
Chloral hydrate is a hypnotic sedative.
클로랄 하이드레트는 최면 진정제에요
There were no traces of anything like
that found in Veronica Sorensen.
베로니카 소렌슨에게서 발견된 것과
같은 약물의 흔적은 없었어요
Which means if our guy still sedates his
victims before sexually asphyxiating them,
그러니까 범인은 희생자를 성적으로
질식시키기 전에 진정제를 투입한다는 건데
whatever he's using
now isn't leaving a trace.
지금 사용하고 있는 건
흔적이 남지 않는 거라는 얘기군
- Warrick Brown.
- Mike Keppler.
- 워릭 브라운입니다
- 마이크 케플러요
I know...
압니다
You trying to do a geographic
profile of your serial?
연쇄살인의 지리적 분석을 하려는 건가요?
Yeah,most of these guys tend
to operate out of one place.
네, 이런 범인들 대부분은
한 장소에서 행동하는 경향이 있거든요
In theory, as the killer gets more
and more comfortable with each act,
이론적으로 살인자는 범행을
저지를수록 점점 대담해지면서
the locations of the bodies should
spiral outward from one central point
시체의 위치가 하나의 중심부에서
나선형 바깥쪽으로 뻗어가게 됩니다
I tell you one thing that your
dump sites do have in common.
시체가 버려진 곳의 공통점을
하나 말씀드리죠
What's that?
그게 뭐죠?
When the bodies were found,
the location that they were found in
시체가 발견되었을 때 발견 장소가
at the time had the highest
crime rate in the city.
그 당시에는 이 도시에서 범죄율이
가장 높았던 곳이라는 거죠
Smart.
훌륭하네요
The crime center sure seems
to move around pretty quickly here,huh?
확실히 범죄 중심 지역이
꽤 빨리 이동하는 거 같은데요?
Well,in Vegas, new is old in five years,
라스베가스에서는 5년이 지나면
새것이 헌 것이 되고
old is history in ten,
and nothing ever seems to leave a mark.
10년이 지나면 헌 것은 역사가 돼버려서
아무것도 흔적을 남겨두지 않게 되죠
Sounds refreshing.
재미있네요
'89 Jane Doe, this was your case.
89년의 신원 미상자, 이 사건을 담당하셨더군요
One of the first homicides I ever worked.
처음으로 맡은 살인 사건 중 하나였죠
Damn, I had good handwriting.
Excuse me.
글씨를 잘 썼네요
잠깐만요
Come on,come on,
I know you got company.
자, 어서
동행이 있다는 걸 알고 있다고
Yeah, that's it.
그래, 바로 그거야
Oh,man.
이런
You processed a mountain of evidence
but didn't turn up a single suspect.
많은 증거를 처리하셨는데
용의자는 한 명도 찾지 못했더군요
It's not my fault,man.
그건 내 잘못이 아니요
I had the scumbag dead to rights.
난 확실히 그 쓰레기 자식을 찾아냈어요
What are you talking about?
무슨 말이죠?
There's nothing here
to indicate that you...
당신이 찾아냈다는 건
여기 없는데요
This is it.
That's the killer's hair.
이거요
살인범의 머리카락이죠
You did note morphology
consistent with the vic.
피해자의 것과 모양이
일치한다고 쓰셨는데요
Yeah, but the position- location was all wrong
그래요, 하지만 방향이나 위치가 전부 틀렸어요
I pulled that out of her navel,
just that one hair.
저걸 배꼽에서 찾아냈죠
저 머리카락 하나만요
It was a sexual assault,
It had to be from the killer.
그건 성폭행 사건이었고
틀림없이 살인자의 머리카락이에요
But I couldn't prove it,
so... I didn't write it down.
하지만 증명할 수가 없었고
그래서 기록하지 못했습니다
This hair had a tag.
Did you run DNA?
머리카락에 모근이 붙어있는데요
DNA 검사는 하셨나요?
In '89?
1989년에요?
Man,we were just reading about DNA.
DNA에 대한 글을 읽기는 했었죠
The only lab in the country that
was doing that stuff was the FBI,
이 나라에서 그런 걸 할 수 있는
연구실은 FBI밖에 없었어요
and my supervisor--
내 상사가
he wouldn't have called
them in on a case like this.
이런 사건에 FBI를
불러주지는 않았을 거요
I used to bust my ass
to keep a crime scene pristine,
범죄 현장을 원상태로 유지하려고
애를 쓰고 있으면
and then some uniform would
wobble over, stuffing his face,
경찰관들이 마구 먹어대면서
여기저기 돌아다니다가
drop a hamburger wrapper right at my feet.
Who the hell needs that?
내 발에다 햄버거 포장지를 떨어뜨리곤 했죠
그게 무슨 소용이 있었겠소?
Man,if I had the tools you guys do today...
댁들이 요즘 가진 장비들이 나한테 있었다면
...I finally would have been a real hero.
난 진짜 영웅이 될 수도 있었을 거요
There's your money shot.
돈 될만한 장면인데요
- Damn it.
- Did you preserve the hair?
- 빌어먹을
- 머리카락은 보관해 두셨나요?
Permount on a microscope
slide with a cover slip.
현미경 슬라이드에 커버 글라스를 덮고
퍼마운트로 봉입했죠
It should still be in Central Property.
아직 본부 보관실에 있을 거요
Are your sure it's really here?
정말 여기 있는 게 확실한가요?
As I said when you called,
we have no record.
전화할 때 말씀드렸듯이
기록이 없습니다
Sir, I spent half the day at Central Property
going through their records.
본부 보관실 기록을
반나절 동안 검토했습니다
Now,according to the case logs,
사건 일지에 따르면
it was transferred to this crt
in late 1989 and never returned.
1989년 말에 이 법원으로 이관된 다음
반환되지 않았으니까
So, it's got to be here somewhere, okay?
틀림없이 여기 어딘가 있을 겁니다, 아시겠습니까?
Okay.
알겠습니다
So it is.
이거네요
Excuse me, bro.
실례합니다
You rang?
불렀어요?
Yeah, I think I need a hand here, Hodges.
네, 도움이 필요해서요, 하지스
Well,what is this?
흠, 이게 다 뭔데요?
It's from an '89 Jane Doe.
89년 신원 미상자에게서 나온 건데
I'm looking for anything
probative that will help us out.
도움이 될만한 증거를 찾고 있어요
Those look like rat droppings.
쥐 똥처럼 생겼네요
That's because they are rat droppings,man.
진짜로 쥐 똥이거든요
Are you familiar with the hantavirus?
한타 바이러스라고 아세요?
Carried by rodents,
transmitted to humans
설치류의 감염된
소변이나 침, 배설물에서
when they inhale vapors from
contaminated urine, saliva or feces.
나온 기체를 들이마시면
인간에게로 전염되죠
That crap will kill you. / Hodges...
그 배설물이 당신을 죽일걸요 / 하지스
glove up.
장갑 껴요
If I start leaking blood from
my eyeballs, I'm blaming you.
내 안구에서 출혈이 시작되면
그건 당신 탓이에요
Keppler?
케플러?
Didn't they give you an office?
사무실을 주지 않던가?
I,uh... I like the noise.
It helps me to concentrate.
시끄러운 게 좋아서요
집중하는 데 도움이 되거든요
I prefer things quiet myself.
Of course,I am a pathologist.
난 조용한 걸 좋아한다네
난 병리학자거든
I reviewed that Jane Doe autopsy from '75.
75년 신원 미상자 검시 보고서를 검토해봤네
That was fast.
빨리 끝내셨네요
Well,I'm sure the original
examination was,too.
최초 검시도 분명히
빨리 끝났을 거야
M.E. was a hack named Sam Barnard.
검시관은 샘 버나드라는 작자였어
He,uh,retired a little while after I started.
내가 이 일을 시작하고 얼마 후에 은퇴했지
Once saw him do a Y with a scalpel
in one hand and a hot dog in the other.
한 번은 한 손에 메스, 다른 손에 핫도그를 들고
Y 절개술을 하는 걸 봤지
I take it he wasn't known for his,
uh,rigorous analysis?
정밀한 해부로 유명하지는
않았다는 걸로 받아들이겠습니다
He was known for liking hot dogs.
핫도그를 좋아하는 걸로 유명했지
Well,that's just great.
훌륭하네요
You know,if you really want to figure
out what killed your Jane Doe,
피해자의 사망 원인이 뭔지
정말로 알아내고 싶다면
there's pretty much only one thing we can do.
할 수 있는 건 대개 한 가지밖에 없지
See the sutured cut across the top
of her head and the Y-incision?
머리 위의 봉합 절개와 Y 절개가 보이나?
No. / It's because they're not there.
아니요 / 한 적이 없기 때문이야
So the original M.E.
didn't even do an autopsy?
그럼 처음 검시의가
검시도 하지 않았다는 건가요?
What can I say?
He was a lazy bastard.
뭐라고 해야 할까...
게으른 놈이었거든
That's criminal malfeasance.
말도 안 되는 위법 행위인데요
Well, if you want to tell him,
I can dig him up, too.
직접 말하고 싶다면
그 작자도 파내 줄 수 있어
Ah, right.
So what do you got?
아, 그렇군요
그럼 찾아내신 게 있나요?
Check out the hyoid bone.
설골을 한번 보게
It's fractured.
골절되어 있네요
Yeah, it doesn't take much force to do it,
그래, 그러는데 힘이 크게 들지는 않으니까
so it's possible there
were no external marks.
겉으로 나타난 흔적이
없었을 가능성도 있어
So the girl was strangled.
어쨌든 피해자는 목이 졸린 거지
So she is one of ours.
그러니까 같은 피해자인 거네요
Gum line filling.
Silver amalgam.
잇몸 충전재네요
은 아말감이에요
On the outside of the tooth?
치아 바깥쪽에요?
That's a cheap way to do it.
돈이 덜 드는 방법이에요
Old school.
구식이죠
Nowadays,most dentists use epoxy
요즘 치과에서는 대개
and other components to
make it match the enamel.
법랑질을 이어 붙일 때
에폭시나 다른 성분을 사용하죠
I worked a mass fatality fire in Philly.
필라델피아에서 대형 화재 사고를 담당했거든요
Learned a lot about teeth.
치아에 대해서 많이 배웠죠
Well,Veronica Sorensen
had a similar filling in her mouth.
베로니카 소렌슨의 입에
비슷한 충전 자국이 있었어
Jane Doe '99 had traces of
chloral hydrate in her system.
99년의 피해자의 체내에는
클로랄 하이드레트의 흔적이 있었어요
I read that dentists used to use
it to sedate pediatric patients.
치과에서 소아 환자를 진정시키는데
사용한다는 걸 읽은 적이 있어요
Looks like our guy might be a dentist.
범인은 치과 의사인 거 같은데요
Her name is Veronica Sorensen,
이름은 베로니카 소렌슨입니다
and we believe that she
might have been a patient here.
여기 환자였을지도 모른다고
생각하는데요
Oh,yes... that poor girl.
네, 그 불쌍한 여자애네요
I saw her on the news. It's terrible.
뉴스에서 봤습니다. 끔찍한 일이에요
These girls, do you recognize any of them?
이 아가씨들 중에 아는 얼굴이 있나요?
Are those girls dead?
모두 죽은 건가요?
We need you to look
carefully at those, ma'am.
자세히 살펴봐 주셨으면 합니다
I'm sorry. I don't recognize them.
미안하지만 모르겠군요
Well,we're going to have to see
your patient files from 1975 to '99.
1975년에서 99년까지의 환자
서류를 봐야 하는데요
Oh,well,I'm sorry.
Inactive files aren't kept past seven years.
미안합니다
과거 7년간 치료가 없던 서류들은 보관하지 않아요
We just don't have the space.
공간이 없어서요
Can you tell us who worked
on Veronica Sorensen?
베로니카 소렌슨을
담당한 분은 누구셨죠?
I'll have to check.
확인해보죠
We have several dentists on staff.
치과 의사가 여러 명이거든요
Even a few dental students who volunteer.
자원봉사를 하는 치의대 학생도 몇 명 있고요
There we are.
여기 있군요
She saw Dr. Dave.
That's Dr. David Lowry.
데이브 박사님의 진찰을 받았어요
데이빗 라우리 박사님이오
Everyone around here calls him Dr. Dave.
이 근처 사람들은 전부 데이브 박사님이라고 부르죠
How long has Dr. Dave been working here?
데이브 박사님이 여기서 일하신 건 얼마나 되셨나요?
Oh,as long as I have.
And I'm going on my 32nd year.
제가 근무한 만큼 되죠
전 32년째예요
Could you ask him to step out, please?
We'd like to speak with him.
잠깐 나오시도록 부탁해주시겠습니까?
말씀을 나누고 싶은데요
It's 1:15.
1시 15분이네요
He's at the Quality Cafe,
around the corner on Fremont.
프레몬트 가 모퉁이 근처의
퀄리티 카페에 있어요
Second booth on the left
facing the counter.
카운터를 마주보고
왼쪽 두 번째 자리에요
The man is nothing if not predictable.
아주 예상하기 쉬운 사람이죠
Dr. David Lowry?
데이빗 라우리 박사님이신가요?
Everybody calls me Dr. Dave.
모두들 데이브 박사라고 부릅니다
I'm Catherine Willows.
캐서린 윌로우즈입니다
This is Michael Keppler.
We're from the Crime Lab.
이쪽은 마이클 케플러입니다
과학수사대에서 나왔습니다
- Please, join me.
- Thank you.
- 앉으세요
- 감사합니다
Dr. Lowry, we'd like to ask you
about one of your patients...
라우리 박사님, 한 환자에
대해 여쭤보고 싶은데요
Veronica Sorensen.
Is this your work?
베로니카 소렌슨인데요
담당하셨죠?
That was a very sad business.
아주 슬픈 일이었죠
She was a lovely, young girl.
사랑스러운 젊은 아가씨였습니다
She had a gum-line cavity.
Now, normally,
잇몸 충치가 있었죠
요즘은 보통
I would have used enamel resin
치아를 접합하는데 법랑질을
to match the teeth, but this
was on the inside of her mouth,
사용합니다만 이건 입 안쪽에 있어서
so I used amalgam to fill it
because it was less expensive,
아말감을 사용했습니다
더 싸거든요
and she was worried about the cost, and...
그 아가씨는 치료비 걱정을 했거든요, 그런데...
her bill was never paid.
치료비는 지불되지 않았죠
Are these your work as well?
이 사람들도 담당하셨나요?
I have no idea-- I was...
모르겠군요, 전
I was seeing a lot of patients over the years.
많은 환자들을 여러 해 동안 진찰했습니다
Do you know their names?
I mean, that might ring a bell.
이름을 아시나요?
그럼 기억이 날지도 모르겠군요
No,we don't know who they are.
아뇨, 신원은 모르고 있습니다
Do you ever use chloral hydrate?
클로랄 하이드레트를 사용하신 적이 있나요?
No one uses chloral hydrate anymore.
It's too dangerous.
클로랄 하이드레트는 더 이상 사용하지 않아요
너무 위험하거든요
I just feel so awful.
아주 끔찍한 기분이 들어요
Why is that?
왜 그러신가요?
I brightened her smile.
제가 이 아가씨 미소를 환하게 만들어줬거든요
Perhaps that's what attracted her predator.
그게 살인자의 관심을 끌었을지도 모르잖아요
Oh,well...you'll forgive,
but if you don't have any more questions,
죄송하지만 질문할 게 더 없으시다면
I really should get back to my office.
병원으로 돌아가야 되겠군요
Whoever did your mouth...
치과의가 누군지 모르겠지만
he does lovely work.
아주 훌륭하군요
- Thank you
- See you tomorrow, Dr. Dave.
- 감사합니다
- 안녕히 가세요, 데이브 박사님
I don't know,
kind of reminds me of my Uncle Ralph.
모르겠어요
랄프 삼촌을 약간 생각나게 하는데요
Except for the serial killer part, I hope.
삼촌께서 연쇄살인범은 아니길 바라요
I haven't seen him for a while. Who knows?
못 본지 오래됐으니 누가 알겠어요?
In the original photograph,
it would've looked like a severe bruise.
원본 사진에서는
심한 멍처럼 보였지만
But there's a lot of information in the negative.
필름에 더 많은 정보가 들어있어요
You know,back in the day, they didn't
have the capability to see this stuff.
아시다시피 그때는 이 자료를
조사할 능력이 없었어요
Pretty distinct impressions
of the six upper teeth.
윗니 자국 여섯 개가
꽤 뚜렷하네요
Yeah. And here, there's a small
gap between the two front teeth.
네, 그리고 앞니 두 개 사이에
작은 틈새가 있습니다
Did Dr. Dave have a space between his teeth?
데이브 박사의 이 사이에 틈이 벌어져 있었나요?
I don't remember.
기억이 안 나
But you can't go in there,
because he's with a patient.
환자분이 있으셔서
들어가시면 안 돼요
Dr. Lowry,
would you please come with us?
라우리 박사님
저희와 함께 가주시겠습니까?
Euginia has been seeing me for, um,
how many years, my dear?
유지니아가 제 진찰을 받아온 것이
그러니까, 그게 몇 년 동안이죠?
I think it's much longer than that.
그것보다는 훨씬 오래됐을 거요
I'd like to finish Euginia up
before the Novocain wears off.
마취가 풀리기 전에
유지니아의 진료를 끝내고 싶은데요
We've got a court order
to collect a bite impression from you.
박사님의 치아 모형을 뜰 수 있도록
법원 명령을 받아왔습니다
Is this about these young girls?
그 젊은 아가씨들 때문이오?
I think you know what this is about, Dr. Lowry.
무엇 때문인지는 아실 거라고 생각하는데요, 라우리 박사님
You're gonna need to come
down to the crime lab with us.
저희와 함께 연구소로 가주셔야 합니다
Bite impression.
치아 모형이라
Couldn't we just do that here?
그냥 여기서 하면 안 되겠소?
It'll save us all a lot of time
and trouble, unless of course,
우리 전부 시간과 수고를
아끼게 될 거요, 물론
embarrassing me in front of
my patient is your real intent.
내 환자 앞에서 날 난처하게 만드는 게
진짜 목적이 아니라면 말이요
Fine.
좋습니다
Okay. Euginia?
좋아요. 유지니아
I'm going to have you wait in Exam Four,
and I'll be in there in just a short while.
4번 진찰실에서 기다리면
잠시 후에 갈게요
No,come on, let's go.
Let's see,just...
아뇨, 자, 갑시다
어디 보자
And you know the upper
right teeth we worked on?
오른쪽 윗니 치료한 거
알고 있죠?
Well,they're looking fine.
좋아 보여요
That's too much water.
It will never set.
물이 너무 많아요
굳지 않을 거요
We've got time.
시간은 충분해요
Young lady,
please, please, please,
아가씨
자, 자
let me do this.
I have much more practice.
내가 하도록 하죠
훨씬 많이 해봤거든요
Be my guest.
그러세요
You know...
I don't believe courts accept
법원에서 더 이상 치아 모양 증거를
bite mark evidence much anymore.
No,they'd much rather have
크게 받아들이지 않는다고 생각하는데요
차라리 상처 주변의 침에서
DNA from saliva around wound.
나온 DNA 증거를 받아들일 테죠
I've gotten convictions from bite marks.
치아 모양으로 유죄 판결을 얻어낸 적이 있어요
Not many,I suspect.
그런 적이 많을 거 같지는 않군요
Do you know that our teeth
우리 치아가 일생 동안
continuously migrate
through our entire life?
끊임없이 변화한다는 거 알고 있소?
Yes.
그래요
Dental forensics
is definitely an inexact science.
치과법의학은 확실히
부정확한 과학이오
We could probably match four out of six.
6개 중 4개는 일치해요
That's not enough for a conviction.
유죄 판결을 받기에는 충분하지 않아요
Has to be.
It's all we've got.
받아내야만 해요
이게 우리가 가진 전부예요
The killer's left front incisor is misaligned.
살인자의 왼쪽 앞니는 고르지 않아요
Dr. Dave's smile is perfect.
데이브 박사의 미소는 완벽하고요
Would you go to a dentist with bad teeth?
치아 상태가 나쁜 치과 의사에게 진찰을 받겠어요?
So we're all on the same page, right?
About giving the man to these girls.
그러니까 모두 같은 의견인 거지?
그 남자가 이 여자애들을 죽인 거라고 말이야
Yes. / So, Mike, the Viewing Room
is down the end of the hall.
네 / 그럼, 마이크, 참관실은
복도 끝에 있네
Wait,why don't you go in and I'll watch.
잠깐만요, 당신이 들어가고 제가 볼게요
What makes you think
he's gonna talk to me?
왜 박사가 저한테
털어놓을 거라고 생각하시죠?
Because I have a pretty good
feeling he's not gonna talk to me.
나한테는 안 털어놓을 거라는
꽤 확실한 느낌이 들거든요
All right.
알았어요
Dr. Lowry, I'd like to show
you a bite impression
라우리 박사님, 소렌슨 사건의
증거로 사용할
that we're using as evidence
in the Sorensen case.
치아 모형을
보여드리고 싶습니다
There are similarities.
But I don't think it's conclusive.
유사점이 있기는 하지만
결정적이라고 생각하지는 않습니다
Yes, they are
The left front incisor doesn't match,
그렇습니다
왼쪽 앞니가 일치하지 않습니다
and there's a sizable gap
between the two front teeth.
두 앞니 사이가 꽤 크게
벌어져 있습니다
But then we found these.
하지만 이걸 찾았습니다
We subpoenaed your personal records.
You go to a good dentist.
개인 기록 소환장을 발부받았습니다
좋은 치과에 다니시더군요
In late 1989,
you had a cosmetic surgery to repair
1989년 후반에
치아 성형술을 받으셔서
a sizable gap between your two front teeth.
앞니 두 개 사이의 큰 구멍을 메우셨더군요
Diastema.
It's called diastema.
치극이요
치극이라고 부르죠
We used the X-rays taken
before the procedure to
치료를 받기 전에 찍은
엑스레이를 사용해서
modify your dental model so that it matched
the configuration of your teeth in 1989.
1989년 박사님의 치아 배열에 일치하도록
치아 모형을 수정했습니다
This is the new overlay.
이게 새 오버레이입니다
Very impressive.
아주 인상적이군요
You make a good case.
멋지게 증명해냈군요
Wasn't easy, Dr. Lowry.
You cover your tracks well.
쉽지 않았습니다, 라우리 박사님
증거를 잘 숨기셨어요
Dr. Dave, please, call me Dr. Dave.
데이브 박사요
데이브 박사라고 불러줘요
Jane Doe in 1975,
Jane Doe in 1989,
1975년의 신원 미상자
1989년의 신원 미상자
and Jane Doe,1999.
Three girls without identities.
1999년의 신원 미상자
신원이 확인되지 않은 소녀 세 명입니다
You were the last person to see them alive.
살아있는 아이들을 마지막으로 보신 분이 당신입니다
You know their names.
Tell us.
이름을 알고 있겠죠
말해 주세요
You have two daughters,
don't you, Dr. Lowry?
따님이 둘 있죠
그렇지 않나요, 라우리 박사님?
This is the most cryptic conversation
I've had since dental school.
치과 대학에 졸업 이후로
가장 알 수 없는 대화로군요
All right,let me clear it up for you.
좋습니다, 분명하게 말해 드리죠
The last time you moved as a free man
was when you walked into this room.
이 방에 들어온 게 당신에겐
자유인으로서의 마지막 행동입니다
When you leave here,
you're gonna be charged with murder.
여기를 나가면
살인죄로 기소될 겁니다
So do yourself a favor,
give us the identity of these three girls,
그러니 부탁하건대
이 세 소녀의 신원을 알려주십시오
and you might spare
yourself the death penalty.
그럼 사형은 면할 수 있을지도 모릅니다
At my age,I'll die before that happens.
이 나이라면 그렇게 되기 전에 죽게 될 거요
So what do you have to lose?
그럼 잃을 게 없지 않나요?
I don't want to degrade
the sweetness of my memories.
내 아름다운 추억들을
손상시키고 싶지 않아요
My memories are all I have left.
내게 남은 건 추억뿐이라오
I can't imagine that you didn't feel
something for these girls at some point.
한번쯤은 이 소녀들에게
미안한 감정을 느끼셨을 거라 생각합니다
We're just asking you
to help us return them to their families.
이 소녀들이 가족에게 돌아갈 수 있게
도와주시지요
What benefit would I get from doing this?
그렇게 해서 내가 얻는 게 뭐죠?
You might sleep better at night.
밤에 잠을 더 잘 주무실 수 있겠죠
I sleep fine, thank you very much.
잠은 잘 자고 있소, 고맙군요
I've always considered
that a key to my good health
그게 내 건강의 비결이라고
늘 생각하고 있다오
So none of this bothers you?
그럼 이 일이 아무렇지도 않다는 건가요?
My life has been blessed.
난 축복받은 삶을 살았소
I was married to a kind woman.
상냥한 여자와 결혼했고
Just lost her a few years ago.
We raised two children.
바로 몇 년 전에 잃었소
우린 두 아이를 키웠는데
One of them is an oral surgeon,
the other one is a homemaker.
하나는 구강외과 의사고
하나는 가정주부라오
And you don't care how this might affect them?
이 일이 따님들에게 어떤 영향을 줄지 상관없으신가요?
They'll be horrified,of course.
물론 충격을 받을 거요
They're not monsters.
그 애들은 괴물이 아니라오
Well,I'm sure the judge
will take that into consideration.
재판관이 틀림없이
그 사실을 참작해줄 겁니다
You're not listening.
내 말을 듣지 않고 있군요
I don't feel bad about what I've done.
내가 한 일을 후회하지 않아요
I feel disappointed that I've been caught,
잡혔다는 게 실망스럽긴 하지만요
but I tend to take the long view of things.
난 긴 안목으로 상황을 보는 경향이 있죠
I've had a wonderful life,
난 멋진 삶을 살았고
and I know that all things
human eventually must end.
인간은 결국 죽는다는 걸 알아요
You have no new messages.
새로운 메시지가 없습니다
번역수정
박수희(wren79@nate.com)
한글수정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)